

### **CLOUD & AI ARCHITECT**

**(**91) 96204 42842

<u>vibhor75.agarwal@gmail.com</u>

Pengaluru (South), India, 560 068

LinkedIn Profile

## professional summary

**Vibhor** brings over 23 years of IT experience and currently serves as a **Cloud & Al Architect**. He possesses extensive knowledge & enterprise solution experience across various business and technology domains. His expertise spans a wide array of tools & technologies, including Cloud, Al & Data domain, DevSecOps, Automation, Java/J2EE, Full Stack, Python, React/Angular, Mobility, Middleware, and Bl/Data Analytics. Vibhor has played pivotal roles in product development, research, prototyping, digital transformation, application modernization, portfolio rationalization, business process automation, and various optimizations.

**Vibhor** is an agile hands-on technologist, experienced with building product strategy/road map, and an expert in architecting, designing, building, complex products and applications.

**Vibhor** currently leads and contributes to various initiatives, including COEs/COPs, business development, technology sales, customer presentations, asset & accelerator creation, recruitment, proposals, POCs/POVs, and providing support across business units.

## education

### **MBA**

**Pune University** 

#### BE

**Bhopal University** 

Secondary & Higher Secondary CBSE

# experience summary

Duration	Organization	Designation
Jul 2003 - Present		
	CGI Inc.	Director Consulting (Expert)
Jun 2002 - Jul 2003	Automated Workflow Private Limited	
	(Now - <u>Azentio, Candela Labs</u> )	Development Specialist
Nov 2000 - Feb 2002	Tata Infotech Ltd (TIL)	
	(Now Tata Consultancy Services)	Trainee, Development Engineer

## certifications

- AWS Certified AI Practitioner
- Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2024 Generative Al Certified Professional
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2023 Certified Multi Cloud Architect Associate
- Career Essentials in Cybersecurity by Microsoft and LinkedIn
- Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals
- Build Your Generative AI Productivity Skills with Microsoft and LinkedIn
- HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate
- AWS Partner: Accreditations
- Microsoft Certified Azure Al Fundamentals
- Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2024 Certified Foundations Associate
- Certified SAFe® 5 Practitioner

- Neo4J Certified Professional
- Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2023 AI Certified Foundations Associate
- Oracle Cloud Data Management 2023 Certified Foundations Associate
- Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2021 Certified Architect Associate
- Al for Organizational Leaders by Microsoft and LinkedIn
- Career Essentials in Generative AI by Microsoft and LinkedIn
- Google Cloud Certified Cloud Digital Leader
- Career Essentials in GitHub Professional Certificate
- Google Cloud Skills
- Aviatrix Certified Multi-Cloud Networking Associate
- Microsoft Certified Azure Data Fundamentals
- Python for Data Science
- Certified SAFe 5 Agilist

## skill snapshot

Core languages/frameworks	Python, Java, Ruby on Rails, PL/SQL, Microservices	
Front End	React, Angular, jQuery, Ext JS, Oracle OAF, JSP, JPF	
Cloud	AWS, Oracle Cloud Infrastructure, Google Cloud, Azure, Cloud Foundry	
AI & ML	Big Data processing, RAG, AI with public Cloud, OpenAI, Machine Learning/ Models (with AWS	
	Sagemaker), Microsoft Teams Bot	
Middleware	Redis, Rabbit MQ, IBM MQ, Tibco, WebSphere CI	
laC	Serverless, AWS CDK, Terraform, Azure Bicep	
QA	Pytest, Locust, JMeter, Selenium, BDD, Ranorex, Rest Assured	
DevSecOps	Jenkins, Azure DevOps, Veracode, Coverity, Black Duck, AppDynamics, SonarQube, Kubernetes,	
	Docker, GitHub Actions	
CMS	Jahia, Tridion, Liferay, WordPress	
Data, Bl	Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL, NoSQL, Grafana, Hadoop, BigQuery	
Exposure to	ELK, Kafka, Service Mesh, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Azure Data Factory, Databricks, PySpark, Snowflake,	
	IoT	

## key assignments

- Driving Al and Data initiatives for a bearing manufacturer, including Big Data processing / Data Lake on AWS, Azure
  Al / GenAl based product assistant, 'MS Teams' bot, ML prototypes with AWS Sagemaker, custom model deployments,
  scientific UI with React
- Digitalization of desktop applications on AWS for a bearing manufacturer, with Python, Lambda APIs, containerization with ECS & other serverless technologies in a custom, secure, cost-effective, high-performance, & scalable architecture
- For a semiconductor manufacturer, built a Java, AWS & Angular based solution that digitalizes NCF payment cards integrating with MDES and VTS. Other assignments included building an OpenID based AuthN & AuthR system with user's digital identity
- End to end automation & optimization of Content & Services platform for a navigation systems & map provider
- CMS migration (Tridion to Jahia) & enhancement of content management portal for a French Facilities Management provider.
- Oracle EBS customization (OAF, PL/SQL) for a US based gas detection company
- Application portfolio rationalization & modernization (Java, MQ, Oracle) for a custom brokerage services provider
- Development of a complex WebLogic portal (SOA, J2EE, Oracle) providing hedge funds services for a large German bank

Note: For all assignments & details, please ask for complete resume

# trainings, publications

- Blogs/Papers:
  - https://techvibhor.link
  - https://dev.to/vibhor\_agarwal/customized-scaling-of-aws-ecs-39ge
  - https://stackoverflow.com/collectives/aws/articles
- Tech Community
  - https://stackoverflow.com/users/7746398/techfree
  - <a href="https://github.com/vibhoragarwal">https://github.com/vibhoragarwal</a>
- Training Kubernetes Administrator (CKAD), GCP, WebLogic, MongoDB, Intershop, Talend, Liferay, Jahia, Angular, Agile, Data Science, Design Thinking
- Industry Experience Manufacturing, Banking, Telecom, Retail & Consumer Services, Product Development,
   Digital Payment